<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Martial arts on ISBA Budapest dojo</title><link>/en/categories/martial-arts/</link><description>Recent content in Martial arts on ISBA Budapest dojo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>hu-hu</language><atom:link href="/en/categories/martial-arts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iaijutsu</title><link>/en/iaijutsu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/iaijutsu/</guid><description>
Iaijutsu
After we learned the basics (welcomes, suit, stands, sittings, defences, cuts), we learn the steps of attack and defense, form of practice (kata) from the positions of standing, - sitting, - walking; all of them are organised to schools (ryû), with the weapons bellow:
Shinai (bamboo sword) Katana (samurai sword) With katana we practice 6 ryû:
Shinto Munen ryû tachi iai Rikishin ryû Ryugo ryû Keishi ryû Araki ryû Sekiguchi ryû</description></item><item><title>Kenjutsu</title><link>/en/kenjutsu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/kenjutsu/</guid><description>
We practice in pair with bokken (wooden sword) while we learn the different schools, which has 10 kata (techniques) each.
Tachi dori (bare hand against sword) Kumi uchi (bokken against bokken) Rikishin ryû Kenjutsu bokken against bokken) Ryu ko ryu Kenjutsu (bokken against bokken)</description></item><item><title>Kobudo</title><link>/en/kobudo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/kobudo/</guid><description>Practicing different self-defence techniques with tools by Japanese traditions.
Bo (long stick) Hanbo (half-long stick) Tanbo (short stick) Tan-sai-bo (mini stick) Jitte (short iron stick) Bachi (drumstick) Jo (chopsticks) Kusarigama (sickle chain) Tessen (steel fan) Kama (sickle) Tetsugusari (chain) Defence against knife Defence against pistol hanbo, tanbo, tan-sai-bo tetsugusari kusarigama tessen, tokko, te-no-uchi</description></item><item><title>Modern Jujutsu</title><link>/en/onvedelem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/onvedelem/</guid><description>punches, kicks and escapes from different grabs (eg. choking, hugging, etc), learning simple take downs with imaginable enemies at first, then with our training partner we learn how to fall &amp;ldquo;well&amp;rdquo;, without any injuries the technics what we learnt smoothing towards with situational practice, until these will come from reflex besides the useful technics we increase our physical power to being more fit and confident the self defence is built to Nihon Jujutsu Japanese martial art, which is several hundred years old but not outdated at all during the trainings we also develop our self-confident - in a possible attack we have to defence ourselves and use what we learnt.</description></item><item><title>Nihon Jujutsu</title><link>/en/nihon-jujutsu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/en/nihon-jujutsu/</guid><description>The Jûjutsu is one of the most anciant Japan combat martial art. It’s Ju Jutsu an independent system with own training thematic.
What is the different between: Jûjutsu, Ju Jutsu, Ju Jitsu, Jiu Jitsu? Actually nothing. In the speaks of Japanese the sounds is Jujutsu but the English people started to use the name Ju Jitsu. Than to make it more difficult, German people and other nations are using it as Jiu Jitsu.</description></item></channel></rss>